此片献给那些致力于保卫国家 民主自由 防止恐怖袭击和暴政专制的英雄们
这些人会在未来某天被召集到一起...
行动
勇者
就是希望.
本片改变自真实勇者事迹
我父亲临终前曾说
Just before my father died,
人暮老最可怕的
he said the worst thing about growing old
便是守护心爱之物会变得力不从心
was that gets harder to protect the things that matter.
荣誉 自由
HONOR, FREEDOM
正义还有亲情
JUSTICE and FAMILY
全都无比神圣
Those things are sacred
你天天循规蹈矩的生活
You live your life by a code, an ethos
人人如此
every man does
这是引你回家
it's your shoreline
的希望
that's what guides you home
相信我
and trust me,
回家就是你唯一的期盼
you're always trying to get home.
海豹第七突击队 高跳低开训练
SEAL Team 7
HALO jump training -
圣地亚哥 加州
San Diego, CA
菲律宾
PHILIPPINES
当局称首相维尔贝克参观了
哥斯达黎加商业中心...
与毒品交易有关...
在泰国使用一种...
25000多种...
我也想去买冰淇淋
Can I get some ice cream?
不行 我们得走了
No, we gotta go
你总说不行
You always say no
那你自己会买吗?
Well, you gonna buy?
不 你去买!
No, you buy!
好吧 今天要什么口味的?
Ok, what do we getting today?
百香果
Passion fruits.
好 就百香果
Ok, passion fruits.
声称对马尼拉国际学校的袭击事件负责
... claim responsibility for the attack at the International School in Manila ..
你父亲是个书虫
Your father was a reader
丘吉尔
He loved Churchill
福克纳 还有其他智者的书都是他的最爱
Faulkner, and books about other wise men
他至爱盒子上伟人的彩绘
He loved the heart of supreme people with boxes for buddies
这是我无法理解之处
I don't give a hell about that
而他却说"你还需努力挖掘"
and he said, "you gotta look harder"
马格林斯大使一直是
Ambassador Marguilles had long been
该地区反恐行动的强力支持者
a strong supporter of Joint Counter Terrorism Operation conducted within this region.
目前仍无任何组织声称
Not one group has yet claim responsibility for
对国际学校的袭击事件负责
the attack on the International School ...
这是你的咖啡 罗克
Here's your coffee, Rorke
谢谢 女士
Thank you, Maam
情况怎么样?
How is it going?
不错 一切照旧?
Great, you want the usual?
好的 谢谢
Sounds good, thank you.
晚点再谢 戴夫
Late again, Dave
戴夫
年度最佳海军
入驻美军大平洋司令部五次
入驻美军中央司令部两次
SOC-Dave
sailor of the year.
PACOM-5 tours
CENTCOM-2 tours
我可没这么说过
I didn't say it..
你接来下打算在这做什么?
What do you got going on over here?
THE EXPECTANT FATHER
Facts, tips and tricks for the expectant father
不是吧 兄弟?
Are you serious man?
我们还没告诉其他人
We're not telling anyone yet
你看上去很紧张
You look nervous alot
上次我打电话过去 他们都不在
Well, last time I checked they don't come with directions
快讲讲事情经过
Yeah, tell me about it
我兄弟要当爸爸了
Hey, my man here's having a baby.
嘿 恭喜啊!
Hey, congratulations!
伙计们 罗克要当爸爸了!
Hey everybody, Rorke's having a baby!
我刚怎么说来着?
What did I just said?
哦 别担心 兄弟 你肯定是个好爸爸
Oh, don't worry about it man, you're gonna be awesome.
我太激动了 你会是个好爸爸
I'm so exciting for you man, you're gonna be a good dad.
杰克 明天我要和桑迪和孩子们
Hey tomorrow Jack, you know, heading down to the beach
去海边 我会给你带冲浪板去的
Bring Sandy and the kids, I'll bring an actual board for you
你知道我不冲浪
You know I don't surf.
这不是重点 联络家人感情才是目的
I know you don't surf, but it'll good to get families together.
既然你都在酒吧昭告天下了 那明天你得来
But now that you've told everyone in the bar, trying to contained yourself tomorrow
我尽量
I will try.
哥斯达黎加
COSTA RICA
父亲还是那句"去努力挖掘"
"Look harder", your father would say
但愿不是指他画的那些奇怪盒子上的彩绘
I wish knew he wasn't just talking about those strange box he paintings
或是这个人们各具伪装的
Or ordering chaos enwrap the world.
混沌纷乱的世界
One often disguise as the other
- 会很疼.. - 不 你就觉得有点刺痛
- It's hurt.. - No, you'll just feel a little bit tingling
大家过得好吗?
How you guys doing, huh?
克里斯托!
Christo!
嗨 我马上下来 等下?
Hey, I'll be right down, all right?
你说了算 老大
Whatever you say, Boss.
旅途如何?
How was arrive?
我今早从哥伦比亚出发的
I left Colombia this morning
从哥伦比亚到这就花了一天?
Colombia to here in a day?
唬你的
It's a gag
不管怎样 据说克里斯托身价达上亿
Anyway, estimate says that Christo worth close to a million
他值这么多?
That's he would be?
是啊 而且这里的社区都有他的捐款
Yeah, and he gives back a lot to this community over here
医疗诊所 学校 财政资助 遍地都是
with medical clinics, schools, political donations, you name it
关键就在这里 这里人对他忠心耿耿
So this is the deal, they are extremely loyal to him over here.
药品管理局什么时候开始袖手旁观了?
When did the DEA have a mobile dwarf?
从他们拦截那架
When they intercepted a 707 of his field with
装满苏联武器的707的时候吧
Soviet weapons
我们的同行窃听了国家安全局
This is among us. These boys overheard NSA,
还发现了些有趣的线索表明克里斯托
they found some interesting hints connecting Christo
和东南亚的恐怖组织有关
toward Jihadist network out this South East Asia
显然 克里斯托同伙中有人在操控这个组织
Apparently, Christo one of the guys running the network.
他们是发小
They're childhood friends
你曾祖父曾是B24型战斗机的飞行员
Your father's grandfather gave up his life piloting a B-24
也因此死于二战
on World War II
为了给战友争取跳伞时间 他坚持驾驶
He kept to level her just long enough for everyone else to jump
才因来不及跳伞而和飞机一起坠毁
and then he went down with the plane
你和他一脉相连
That's the blood that courses through your veins
爸爸 我能跟你一起去冲浪吗?
Daddy, can I come with you?
想跟我去? 你知道那有多冷吗?
Wanna come with me? Did you  feel how cold it is out there?
我说 你先跟妈妈逛一会 帮忙照顾下宝宝
I tell you what, go hang out with mommy for a little while, help out with the baby
等我回来 如果你还想去 我就带你一起去
when I came back in, if you still wanna go out. I'll take you out with me.
说话算数?
Promise?
我保证 快点 去吧
I promise. Hurry up, go.
- 怎么了 兄弟?  - 怎么了 伙计?
- What's going on, Sir? - What's up, Brother?
没什么 兄弟
Not too much, man
我知道你们纽约人做事总满腔热血
Oh, I know you got the New York heritage,
但这可不是在圣岛上度假
but this isn't exactly like sitting back on Santa Island
你可真要卯足劲才行
You're gonna actually work hard to get through this Sir
是啊 我明白 我懂
Yes, I know, I know
常规事项再附加12条注意
twelve plus series of routines.
你知道怎么冲吗?
And you don't know  how to do this?
等有了五个孩子 你就懂了 伙计
Hey, wait until you have 5 kids,  man.
来看看你冲浪玩的如何
Let's see how much time you got playing the surf.
准备好呛水了吗?
You ready to get the drink or what?
好吧 伙计 你带路
All right man, you lead the way.
- 好的 别给丢脸呐!  - 恩
- All right, don't embarrass us! - All right.
你父亲是我的长官 我是他的左右手
Your father was my boss  and I was his chief
我们都不止一次救过对方
We've saved each other's lives more than once
我们兄弟情深
It was a brotherhood between us
我们依靠彼此胜过依靠家庭
and we depended on each other more than family
智者曾说团结就是力量
Wise men once said, aLThough a single twig will break, a bundle of twig is strong
哇哦 真是难以置信
Wow, this is unbelievable.
我还是不相信你在这点中餐
I can't still believe you order Chinese in this place.
味道确实不错
It's really good.
双字得分 十八分
double word score, 18 points.
两个?
DUMB?
你不知道是哪个 是吧
You don't know which, Sugar
我可不想
I try not to
看看这个 看看 我得了三十八分
look at this, look at this, 38 points for me
ADumbrating? 没这单词
ADUMBRATING? That's even not a word.
好吧 首先它读作Atombrading
Ok, first of all, it's pronounced "atombrading"
然后意思是"假装 有伏笔"
and it means "pretending" , " foreshadowing"
嗯 猜猜今晚谁买单 亲爱的?
Hmm.. guess who's buying dinner tonight. Sugar?
好吧
Fine.
多数情况下 办公室适用战术性妥协
Most cases offices get tactical pardons
英语搞得我都快成 拼字骗子了
Language has me up for some sort of...scrabble hustler
拼字大师 好吗? 搞清楚
Scrabble Yoda, okay? Get it right.
- 多少钱? - 算了吧
- How much do I owe you? - Nada
我们队总是处于整装待发的状态
Our platoon was had it downranged
威米 是我们的狙击兵 十年前
Weimy, he's our sniper. Ten years ago,
他能在杂货店货架的袜子堆里埋伏一整晚
he worked a night stocking shelves at groceries store.
如今的夜晚 他成了另一种守卫者
Now he's another watchman standing guard
作为丈夫和父亲
while the world sleeps. He's a husband and a father
雷曾是我们的联络员 无线电员
Ray was our communications guy,our radio man.
他来自洛杉矶东区黑帮
He grew up in East LA gangland.
因助受伤的队伍脱离险境而荣获银星勋章
He has a silver star for deploying wounded team made out of a fried
桑尼 他坚若磐石
Sonny, he was made of granite
这家伙都不会做俯卧撑
This guy didn't even do push-ups '
因为他的胸肌太发达了
cause was afraid his chest was gonna get too big
阿加伊三十岁后才加入队伍 他早年打泰拳
Ajay, joined the team late in his 30's.
在那之前他在特立尼达拉岛港口长大
He'd been a Muay Thai fighter early in life. Before that, he grew up Derp Port in Trinidad.
米奇在队里呆了二十年
Mikey had 20 years in the teams
低调如他 你都不会注意到他
As humble as he was, you'd never even know it.
他把放了妻子的照片放在头盔里
He kept a picture of his wife in his helmet
还在口袋里放了她一绺头发 他静如处子
and a lock of her hair in his pocket. Quite as a breeze.
最后就是高级士官长
And finally Senior Chief,
真心不能泄露他太多情况
couldn't really tell you much about him
和他对质对我来说就是以卵击石
Rather than I'd take a knife into gun fighting after being interogated by him.
在家的最后一晚
That last night at home,
你还在钻研怎么做个好爸爸 好丈夫
you think about how you could've been a better dad, a better husband
甚至忘了结婚纪念日和孩子的睡前故事
that bedtime story should've read that our anniversary you forgot
你从不期望家人会理解你的工作
You don't expect your family to understand what you doing
只要让他们明白
just help them to understand
你是为了他们才这么做 那就够了
you do it for them
然后当你归家时 你希望能再次重拾旧日生活
And when you get home, you hope you can pickup right at where you left off.
- 放堆野生木柴? - 嗯
- Put the wild bunch down? - Yeah
嗨 长官 能给我们看看阿什本的地图吗?
Hey, Senior. Do you mind to give us a scope for the ashburn?
好 我找找
No, I might got that thing.
谢谢
Thanks
兄弟们 你们知道我平时总是喜欢长篇大论
Hey fellas, you know how will I got so many speeches
潜心于部署 但是
and give in work-up for the deployment, but uh...
正如我和士官长所说 一旦入队
It's like Chief and I said, right at the beginning of this platoon
一旦我们步入战场 一旦我们整装待发
Once we step off on campaign, once it reversed ready for downranged,
一心回家的念头就该抛之脑后
everything back home is be unbalanced
虽不知会谁死谁生 但步入战场
we will not worth the dead of each other or self,
我们要心无留恋
we get over there, something out of recommendative
家中纠纷 钱财紧缺还有其他一些琐事
Things aren't right with the family,
你都需抛之脑后 所以
things aren't right with the finance or something's off. It's gonna put us all out of balance. So..
这点在出发前每个人都要铭记于心
we need to had that typed before we launch.
还有疑问吗 现在就说
Have somebody got an issue, bring it on
士官长会关照 我也会
Chief can take care, I can take care.
这里的每个人都是彼此的后盾
Everybody's got each other's back.
出发前希望大家明确一点
Let's make sure we lock that down,
完成任务是我们唯一的目的
when we ride or roll. All our focus is on the mission.
为那些已经牺牲的战友
For all those been downranged,
为我们和爱我们的人 干杯!
to us and those like us, damn few. Cheers!
我还是喜欢詹姆斯这个名字
I still like the name James.
我考虑看看 如果是个男孩的话
I'll think about it, it's a boy.
过来我抱抱
come here
我真为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
谢谢你 亲爱的
Thanks, Baby.
嗨 小家伙 看着你妈妈别让她碰鲭鱼
hey liitle one, you make sure you keep mama away from mackerel.
那味道我相当不待见
I don't like that change smoking at all
- 遵命 中尉 - 那就好
- I got it, Lieutenant - OK
要完好无缺的回来
Try to keep these as long as you can, for a while
- 还有吗 长官? - 嗯
- Anything else, Commander? - Yeah
我希望我们第一个孩子出生时 你能在场
I'd like to be able looking your eyes when our first child is born
我会尽力的
You know I'll do my best
- 我爱你 宝贝 - 我爱你
- I love you, Baby - I love you
战争是国家意志的体现
War is a country of will
容不得半点同情
there's no room for sympathy
如果你不愿放弃一切
If you not willing to give up everything
那你会有所失去
You've already lost
把电话给她 吉尔伯托
Get the phone to her, Gilberto
给 长官
Here. Chief.
你想干什么?
What do you want?
我是从墨西哥来的医生 你想干什么?
I am a doctor from Mexico, what do you want?
我们来谈谈你们美国人
Tell me, what is it about you Americans,
凭什么干涉我赚钱生计之路?
that make you feel entitle to fcuk with the way I make my living?
乌克兰
UKRAINE
我叫丽莎・沃恩 是名从墨西哥来的医生
My name is Lisa Vaughn, I am a Doctor from Mexico
我都说了我不知道 你还想怎样
I told you a thousand times I don't know
我知道你的真实身份 莫拉莱斯小姐
I know who you are Miss Morales
我还知道你为谁效力 我们何不省点时间
and I know who you work for, so why don't you save us both  some time
把你知道的都坦白了吧
and tell me exactly what you think you know.
我在照顾给你生孩子的母亲们
I take care the mothers who give birth to your kids.
那感觉如何 莫拉莱斯小姐?
How does that feel Miss Morales?
在斯帕过的美好时光
Have a great day at the Spa.
关掉扬声器!
Turn off the speaker!
别弄死她还有别再给我打电话
Keep her alive and do not call me, anymore
遵命 老大
Yes Boss
接着说啊?
are you going to talk?
- 我一无所知 - 说话啊!说啊!
- Nothing, nothing....- speak to me! Speak to me!
嗨 小伙子们 怎么了?
Hey fellas, what's up?
一颗老鼠屎坏了一锅汤 真晦气 对吧
It's hard when two rats screwed and we all suck up, didn't ya?
非洲有人猿泰山吧
Africa had Tarzan.
找位子坐吧 总之 安排如下
Can take a seat.  Anyway, here's the deal.
是时候殊死一搏了
Time to get your frogmen on.
关灯
Lights
三天前 两名中央情报局探员沃尔特・罗斯
Three days ago two CIA agents, WaLTer Ross
和丽莎・莫拉莱斯小姐
and Miss Lisa Morales were ambushed
在哥斯达黎加旅馆内遭到袭击
inside their hotel room here in Costa Rica
攻击者是一群 身份不明的武装分子
by eh..  unknown amount of  heavily armed assholes
不幸的是 罗斯先生已被害 而莫拉莱斯小姐
Unfortunately, Mr. Ross was murdered, and Ms. Morales
被绑架了 据情报所知
has been abducted. We believe that
这群武装分子为米卡勒・卓伊威斯
this is been a work of a guy named Mikhail Troykovich
（又名克里斯托）所雇 电脑会给出他的侧写
A.K.A Christo. LT's going to give you the scanning on him
谢谢 长官 米卡勒・卓伊威斯又名克里斯托
Thanks Senior. Mikhail Troykovich A.K.A Christo
这个家伙被报
This guy's believed has been working
从二十世纪九十年代后期起
cocaine from weapon deals
就游走在俄国黑手党
between the Russian mafia,
哥伦比亚革命武装力量
the FARC guerrillas
和墨西哥毒贩之间
and the Mexican drugs cartels
进行毒品和武器的地下交易
eversince the late 1990's
在她被捕前 莫拉莱斯一直在试图寻找
Now, before she was captured, Morales was working on
克里斯托和这个叫艾比・莎保的家伙
a possible link between our boy Christo
之间有何关联
and this guy, Abu Shabal
神明的真主 世界的主宰者
Glory to Allah, Lord of the world,
创造了我们穆斯林一族 指引我们明路
that has created us as Muslims and delivered us with jihad
用圣战开辟新世界
on His direct Path
遵从真主旨意的人才能在审判日得到和平
Peace be upon those, who's on His direct Path in the Day of Judgement.
在这需要向你们解释一下
on this explanation to you,
我们并不是分裂主义者
we are not separatists.
我们有权阻止你们这些
We're setting on all legal part of anyone
不管是自愿还是被迫
be you an agent are wilingly or unwillingly
成为特工的人
assisting the agenda of genocide
来残害我们的国民
of our people,
来用条条框框的文法限制我们
by demanding that we obey certain rules
想要试图侵占所有穆斯林的国家
and by your continous occupation of all Muslim countries,
在真主阿拉的引领下 我们必须采取行动
With the Grace of Allah, we must exile to this heed
美国佬 我们担惊受怕的活着
America, you'll never be safe,
也不会让你们好过 伟哉真主
until safety becomes a reality for us.Allahu Akbar.
艾比・莎保是一个车臣恐怖分子
Abu shabal is a Chechen terrorist
他与斯兰学校大屠杀事件有关
that associated with the Beslan school massacre
他周旋于印度尼西亚和菲律宾的士兵集训营
He's been jumping between training camps in Indonesia and the Philippines
如今 克里斯托
Now, the connection between Christo
和艾比・莎保之间的关联变得更加捉摸不透了
and Abbu Shabal is so a little bit fuzzy,
但是如果莫拉莱斯在为艾比・莎保做事的话
But if this was the lead that Morales was working on
也许这是他被绑架的原因 长官?
it could be why she was abducted.Senior?
以上就是莫拉莱斯小姐的资料
All right, this is a personal recovery of Miss Morales.
有疑问吗?
All right, who's got questions?
长官 你有敌营里巡逻队人数的
See, Chief. If you have any  update resource, and tell us numbers inside the
最新数据吗?
camp, what about roving patrols?
8到10个人左右
Maybe 8 to 10 Bro
但是我们对巡逻队一无所知
but we don't know anything about roving patrols
所以你只能假设他们布防严密
you just gonna have to assume
这些人也是干这行的
that's all working around the squared away you just did for a living too
长官 我们需要搜寻哪种武器?
Senior, what kind of weapons on target are we looking at?
重型武器 这些家伙是毒贩
Heavy weapons. This guys are narco traffickers,
比如说M2HB这样的
They can have a M2HB
0.5英寸口径的重型机枪 猜不准
for the course out there,we don't know.
所以 如果装的下 我建议你们带上火箭筒
So, if there is a weapons in place out there, I suggest you guys bring rockets
当然 可别把火箭弹当子弹玩
of course rockets and bullets don't match,
尽量保证一击必杀 好了 还有疑问吗?
so make sure you got a clear shot.All right, what else?
有没有情报说她的伤势如何?
Any idea wether she's ambulatory or not?
案发现场有很多血迹
There's ton of blood on the scene,
不过大部分都是罗斯的
and alot of it was Mr Ross'
我们确信莫拉莱斯小姐也受伤了
We confirmed that Ms. Morales may has blood there too
但是这些家伙都是些野蛮人
But these guys are savages.
你们得做好抬着她
So, you're gonna have to assume that she is..
出来的准备  所以带副担架吧
non ambulatory, so you gonna have to bring stuff to carry her out.
两分钟后跳伞
Two minutes to drop
上尉 要让我们抓到这人
Hey LT, got this little know who that guy,
一定要给他点颜色瞧瞧
so we get back we can kick his ass!
你说谁?
What guy?
给你剪了这么挫的发型的理发师
The guy that gave you taht fcuked up hair cut
妈的 不好意思 最后嘲笑光头佬多明尼一次
Fuck. I'm sorry, this should be the last guy to talk put back in Dominican Mr. Clean
我的头和你的金发如出一辙 是吧?
my hair sounds like your gold teeth huh?
- 别这样嘛 - 我们到了
- Don't be like that...!- we're up!!
带上面罩
Masker.
戴夫 我说 当老爸最好不过了
Dave, I tell you what,
除了要换尿布很忧伤外 不过
the only thing better than this right here is being a dad, except for not whole changing diaper thing, but..
反正总要经历的 所以
Same will goes up for me anyway, so..
我还挺期待当爸爸的
I'm actually looking forward to it.
黑胡子 准备 倒数十秒
Blackbeard, ready lauch in 10..
五
Five..
黑胡分队呼叫基地 黑胡分队呼叫基地
Blackbeard - Main, Blackbeard - Main..
这里是黑胡分队艾克彻 无线电测试 完毕
this is Blackbeard Actual radio check, over.
黑胡分队呼叫基地 黑胡分队呼叫基地
Blackbeard - Main, Blackbeard - Main
这里是黑胡分队艾克彻 完毕
this is Blackbeard Actual, over.
收到 这里是基地 已建立通信
Roger Actual, this is Main, we have you Lima Charlie
收到 基地  所有人员已安全着陆
Roger Main, all boots are on the ground. I passed ,T bird.
我方周围有何动静?
Any traffic for my station at this time?
艾克彻  第二路点流通量在增加
Actual, Imagery picked up an increase in traffic at secondary location
敌方主基地的突击部队正在附近
known to be enemy G-R-F-H-Quick from primary target
在六点方向到达 是否收到
The slick boat Windsored at 0600 for your extract. L, copy.
收到 基地
Roger, Main.
准备好没?
You ready?
准备就绪 长官
Roger that Sir,
目标大约在4.7公里外 方位355
we got about  40.7 clicks with 355
出发
Take it out.
皮鞭分队 一分钟准备
Whiplash, 1 minute out
三十秒
30 seconds
十秒倒计时
10 by 10
皮鞭分队 跳!
Whiplash, go!
全员已登船!
All foots are decked!
绳索安全脱离!
Line secure!
皮鞭分队 "2-1黎明号"撤离
Whiplash, pack "the morning" 2-1 out
皮鞭分队 这里是黑胡分队
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard
无线电测试 完毕
radio check, over.
皮鞭分队呼叫黑胡分队 是否清楚收到
Blackbeard - Whiplash, have you loud and clear
收到 皮鞭分队 预计几分钟到达我方地点
Roger Whiplash,  what is your ETA to my post?
预计二十分钟 原地待命
ETA 20 minus. Stand by.
剃刀（手抛式无人机）已起飞
Razor is in flight,
正向你方靠近
approching to your location
不要 求你了 我受不了了
No more, please, please, I can't, I can't take it anymore
长官 我们得行动了
Hey Sir, we gotta go
收到 出发吧
Roger, take it out.
要是你想让我们原地待命
If you like we put stay,
我宁愿自己率军冲进去
and I'd like take you guys with us
长官 我们的后援部队马上赶到
Chief, I got an SPT coming up on step.
我们需要各就各位了
We gotta it ready and push on my post
我待在这里观察地形
While I am here over watch position
和基地保持联系
and I got to keep reporting back to back with Main
- 原地待命 - 收到
- Staying here.  - Roger that.
- 保持警惕 - 明白
- Keep it tight - Got it.
皮鞭分队 这里是黑胡分队
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard
突击部队要提前行动
AssauLT forces moving the target early
急需火力支援
Request immediate fire support
黑胡分队 这里是皮鞭分队 行动吧
Blackbeard, this is Whiplash, do it, copy.
需要火力支援
Acquired fire support.
十五分钟内到达目的地
Proceed to your location in 15 minus.
皮鞭分队 这里是黑胡分队
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard,
准备控制敌方火力
Prep positive control their item
长官 就绪了吗?
Chief, are you set?
长官 等下
Chief, chick hold.
一点钟方向 以塔为基准
One O'clock, base on the tower
搞定
Done
门口障碍清除
Clear to the door
你那些后援都在哪里?
And what happened to the tomatoes?
后方出现两个敌人
I got two escorts coming from the back door
冲进去!
Move in!
清除!障碍全部清除!
Clear! All clear!
威米 十一点钟方向 准备开卡车从侧面逃离
Weimy, 11 O'clock, driver side truck.
看到了
Got him
清除!障碍全部清除!目标已安全!
Clear! all clear!Target secure!
长官 我去找米奇
Chief, I'm gonna get Mikey
上尉 我是长官 目标已安全
LT, this is Chief. The target is secure.
人质等待转移 注意 米奇负伤 米奇负伤
Stand by for confirmation of package. Be advised, Mikey is down, Mikey is down.
报告完毕
Status followed
收到 允许转移
Roger, you have the package
长官 我搜到一个手机
Chief, I got a cellphone
LT LT!
LT, LT!
长官 有两辆敌方车辆正从北方靠近
Chief, it looks like you have two aggressor vehicle approaching from the north
预计一分钟到达
About one minus out
你可以开西门外的卡车在撤离点和我们汇合
You can take the truck outside the west door, meet us at extract
莫拉莱斯小姐 我带你回家了
Miss Morales, I'm going you home
你得回答我几个问题
I just need to ask you a few questions
你母亲的闺名是什么?
What's your mother's maiden name?
罗萨莱斯
Rosales
你在哪条街出生的?
what street you born on?
霍夫斯普瑞街
Hoffspring
好的 坚持住
All right, just hang on.
皮鞭分队 北方的敌军正往你左方靠近
Whiplash, we have enemy at your left approaching you from the north
收到 我们已确认敌情
Roger, we have identity cue affirmative from the north
长官 你得赶快撤离!
Chief, you need to start your X field now!
我们在第二撤离点汇合
We just set secondary extract
收到
Roger that.
见鬼 长官 这辆车只有1000码远了
Shit, Sir this truck by a thousand yards
现在就撤
Now, taking out.
阿加伊 注意院子里的动机
Ajay, take around the yard, the X we got it here.
还有呼吸 我们得赶快撤离!
It's alive. We gotta get moving now!
威米 快出来!
Weimy, coming out!
在汇合点和我们碰面!
Meet us at rally point!
快撤 快撤!动作快点!
Let's go, let's go! Moving!
右转 右转!
Right turn, right turn!
老兄 看来我们到不了第二汇合点了
Hey man, we're not gonna make this secondary extract
我找其他路线撤退
I gotta find us around employing this road..
米奇 挺住啊
Mikey, come on buddy
长官!
Hey Chief!
我们得换路线!
we're not gonna make secondary extract!
- 这里我说了算! - 遵命!
- You're not to figure it out man! - All right!
挺住啊 坚持住啊 坚持住!
Come on, stay with me, stay with me!
坚持住 挺住啊 米奇!
Stay with me, come on Mike!
醒醒 醒醒 拜托!
wake up, wake up, come on man!
后援队 我们按原定地点汇合
Help Team, we can make it to rally point
太好了 把对讲机给上尉!
Sounds good, pass it to LT!
呼叫上尉 呼叫上尉 这里是突击分队
LT, LT, this is AssauLT Team.
我们已开过第二汇合点
We just lost secondary extract,
重复 我们已开过第二汇合点
I say it again we just lost secondary extract
转移汇合点 报告完毕
Move it to rally point, L copy, over.
现在什么时间了?
- What about the click hour?
米奇 醒醒! 拜托米奇 挺住啊 醒醒!
Mike, wake up!Come on Mike, come on Mikey, wake up!
- 瞄准了吗? - 目标已锁定!
- Got it?  - Axis clear!
开火!
fire!
火箭筒发射!
Rocket out!
快啊 他没呼吸了!
Come on girl. He's not breathing!
我们上车了 我们上车了!
We're up, we're up!
长官 把你的M4步枪给我!
Chief, let me get your M4!
长官 快艇那里情况如何?
Sir, what's the status on those boat?
我在撤离中和皮鞭分队失去了联系
I lost Whiplash on the run.
早说了要早点干掉目标 他们可是来势汹汹
Told you to hit the target early, they're coming in hot
遵命
Roger that.
呼吸啊 米奇 挺住 米奇
Breath Mikey, come on Mikey.
已经没有心跳了!
I got no pulse!
敌方靠近 敌方靠近!
Contact with, contact with!!
我靠!
Holy shit!
加速!加速!
Pick it up, pick it up!
阿加伊 把握好方向盘 敌军在后方!
Ajay, do it all right, they're coming at our rear!
皮鞭分队 皮鞭分队! 准备好登船甲板
Whiplash, Whiplash!Deck at the air extraction first
向第三汇合点行进 我方有八人
Moving to tertiary extract. I have 8 packs
七个队友 一个人质 人质是受伤的莫拉莱斯
7 is around, 1 package. Package is wounded Morales
"内华达"在前面有一个商业区
"The Sierra" has downtown one to the head.
这里汇合点很难办
This will be a hard extract.
他妈什么状况?!
What the fcuk?!
躺下 兄弟 躺下!躺下 兄弟 躺下!
- sit down, man. Get down! - come down brother!
米奇会醒的兄弟 米奇会醒的
Mikey's up man, Mikey's up.
镇定点 老兄! 放轻松
Stay down brother, calm. Be easy,
我们快到了 我们快到了
we're almost outta here.Almost outta here.
- 米奇 挺住啊 - 我们在哪里了?
- Mikey, hang on Buddy. - Where are we?
在去汇合点的路上 现在情况尚佳
On our way to extract. We're good to go
你脸部中枪了 他妈伤的很严重
You took one on the face man, you harm another fcuker
我们杀了他没?
Do we get it?
死了 我杀的 我们在去汇合点的路上
Yes,Oh, I get it ,on our way to extract
阿加伊 冲啊 冲啊!
Ajay, splash it, splash it!
入水!准备入水 入水!
Water! water, water!
我来背她 我来背她!
I got her, I got her!
这并非毫无意义
It wasn't for nothing
乌克兰
UKRAINE
你是谁?
Who are you?
- 是门德尔松吗? - 不 是布拉姆斯
- Is it Mendelsson? - No, Brahms.
我是克里莫夫 你一定是莎保了
I am Kerimov. You must be Shabal.
好吧 就如我在电话里与克里斯托所说
Ok, as I said to Christo on the phone,
我能满足你的需求
I have the requirement you want
就一件背心
a vest
很酷 不是吗?
Cool isn't it?
它看起来普通 但却藏货的好地方
It is simple but effective
过来看
over here
在背心里塞满了瓷制小球
Inside them is tiny balls made of ceramics-based.
每件背心大约能装五百颗
Five hundred of them woven into vest,
小球里放了烈性炸药
They contain explosive gel
这是我们研发的新技术
It is our new technology
很具毁灭性哦
It is truly devastating,
请看
please
不会有问题的
Here is no big deal, you know this
这是专为户外活动设计
It is designed for open spaces
相信我
You have to believe me
这世上鲜有一人专用的武器
There are few weapons in the world that they can operated only by one man
看看这个
Look at this.
它们能躲开任何安检设备的探测
They can go everywhere without get detected
你可以穿着它任游白宫
You could take tour to White House or wherever you like
我能看看演示吗?
Can I see a demonstration?
你开玩笑吧 这会直接送你上西天的
You kidding, you even have no time to go to Siberia
听着 这货要是一爆炸 就直接粉身碎骨了
Listen, when this explodes, there is no safe place.
想象一下五百颗子
Imagine firing 500 bullets
弹瞬间向四面八方扫射的效果
everywhere and being scattered by a massive explosion.
穿着它上台 去赌场或是逛商场
Take one of these to the stage, casino or shopping center
借助美国大众媒体的力量来制造一场大恐慌吧
and create such a massal panic through American mass media.
老兄 看看你 还是没变呐
Buddy, look, you're never change
- 要我给他拿外套吗? - 不用 谢谢
- Can I take his coat? - No, thank you
我一直想见见我的故友
And now from time to time, I get to see my old friends by my old life.
但总是失望而归
And it's always, always disappointing.
要么变成了混蛋 要么变成了无趣之人
Some become asshole, as other boring
简直不敢相信那些年里 我和他们打得火热
And I can't believe I tried to get them in bed all those years ago
嘿 而你 尤里 你却没让我失望
Hey, it is nice not to be disappointed Yuri
我不叫尤里
It's not my name
我知道 你叫穆罕穆德・艾比・莎保
I know. Muhammad Abu Shabal,
莎保之子
the son of Shabal
拜托 但你爸爸叫尤金
Come on, your father's name is Yevgeny
- 事非当年了 - 是啊 时过境迁
- It's changed. - Yeah, I think it's changed
所以时隔多年才和你再次相见
That's why this is the last time I might have to see each other for quite some time.
因为我一直隐姓埋名的活着
For am I have to find a hole to hide in.
我不懂你为什么要这么做
I don't understand
我被中情局盯上了 摆脱不掉他们的监视
I'm being watched by the CIA, and not there gonna be any chances
不言而喻
This is the most oppotunities present itself
我只能举家南迁
I'm taking my family South.
我需要帮助 需要一个有足够实力的人
I need the help, the energy,
或是愿意和那些美国人战到底的人帮我
or the will to fight the Americans
阿戴尔和米歇尔怎么了
What about Ardile and Michel
我费尽心血的
I have devoted much of my respect..
交易依旧成立 尤里 我说我会提前退休
The deal stands, Yuri.Just because I've taken early retirement,
可没说在这期间一直可以讨价还价
does not mean I'm not holding at my end into the bargain
还有很多事没解决呢
There is so much to be done.
会解决的 没有我也行!
And it will be, just without me!
你可以拿我的名声和别人合作
You have to use my trust in associates
- 这对我不利! - 喂!
- It's not so good for me! - Hey!
闭嘴!给我闭嘴!你就会胡说八道!
Hey, shut up! Shut up! Stop! You're fcuking bullshit!
- 你不能这么改革! - 换汤不换药而已
- You can't change it like that! - Nothing changes, nothing.
你刚刚说什么都变了 但是实质却没变?
You just told me everything change,
什么意思? 什么意思?
but what is it? What is that?
你知道我怎么费劲心思到这里的吗?
Do you know, what I do to get here?
你懂吗?
Do you have any idea?
你不知道 你个垃圾
No, you shit,
躲在象牙塔里享乐 没心没肺的活
you live up here, this ivory tower, you are really don't care！
美国理查德军舰 - 中美洲海岸
USS BON HOMME RICHARD - CENTRAL AMERICAN COAST
嗨 长官 米奇情况如何?
Hey Chief, what's the status of Mikey?
眼睛保不住了 但是还在坚强的挺着
He's definitely lose the eye, but he's hang it tough.
我正在看这个
Yeah, I'm gonna get read into this
干得好 教训了这帮混蛋 救回了莫拉莱斯
Great job, small check in those assholes, get Morales back
对米奇来说这会是个教训
It's a blunt deal for Mikey better get
同时也给你们上了一课如何扎实工作
to tell you what was the solid work.
长官 把这话传达下去
So Chief, make sure you get that down of the boys right away.
- 懂不? - 遵命
- Do you hear me? - Sure
好的 还有就是莫拉莱斯
All right. And Morales.
莫拉莱斯就比较难搞了
Morales was one tough chick.
在事情变得难以想象前
But she should've got in this stuff up to change a lot faster
她得尽快恢复帮我们理清线索
because this thing is way bigger than we thought it was.
怎么会变这样?
How was that?
我本以为就是一场切断武器供应的行动而已
I thought this was cut and dry arm search recovery
本来是这样 直到破解了那个手机的内容
Yeah, wasn't until we got into that phone
那只你们从那个鬼地方捡来的手机
that you guys picked up at that shit hole.
想来总觉得事情有些不对劲
It turn me out of something just not look right at all.
觉得什么不对劲?
And what's not right about it?
克里斯托和莎保比我想象的还要密切
Christo and Shabal are a lot closer than I thought they were.
莎保是核心人物
Shabal is a wild core man
他是个老圣战主义者
He's an old jahadi,
对金钱和毒品交易从不掉以轻心
that couldn't give a rest-ass about money or drugs.
所以他的朋友克里斯托也是如此 那个毒贩?
Yeah, that tells his friend Christo, the dope dealer?
他不是毒贩
He's not a dealer man,
他是个走私贩
he's a smugler.
这在玩我吧
You've gotta be kidding me.
我也被耍了 莎保想杀美国人
that is exactly what I'm thinking.
克里斯托知道如何走私入境
Shabal wants to kill Americans, Christo knows how to get fcukers inside America.
大麻烦要降临了兄弟们
This could be big trouble in little timing fellas.
他们想要袭击美国本土
They're gonna hit us at home.
我刚刚和头谈了此事
I just got done talking to boss,
特遣部队的工作部署马上会着手开始
on the spec of task force, this is gonna go down.
让阿加伊和雷待命
I need Ajay and Ray stand by
在两小时内随时准备出发
to launch for NSR in 2 hours.
看来他们是要在去非洲的路上
They gonna get some frigging flower mouse
拦截些花鼠之类的东西了
on the way to Africa.
为什么去非洲
Why Africa?
在手机的资料里发现那里有个机场
We pended airfield there by the phone that you got?
我觉得莎保在西行进行武器交易时会路经那里
And I think that Shabal is gonna be there during weapon transfer on his way West.
你说的西行是指去哪里?
When you say "West", what do we talking about?
墨西哥西部?
Mexico West?
是的
Yeah
墨西哥西部
Mexico West
这是最坏的情况
It's the worst case scenario
你俩还有其余的人都留在这里
You two and the rest of platoon are gonna stay here
待命 如果情况恶化
and  standby, you'll be the primary assault
危机逼近本土 你们会是先发部队
for worst case that goes down anywhere near America
遵命
Check
他们现身时你会在这里吗?
You gonna be around for any questions as they came up?
不行 克里斯托给我摆了一道 然后消失了
No man. Christo, he put a Roman Polanski at my ass and disappeared.
所以我得去和海豹四队取得联络
So I'm gonna link up for SEAL Team 4
我们要去南太平洋把他打个落花流水
and we're gonna go hunt his ass down in the South Pacific
所以说 我可能脱不开身
So straight up, my ties and palm trees so maybe...
放心吧 兄弟 我们会抓到他的
Yeah brother, I go get them
保重 一切顺利
Be cool. take it easy
恭喜你当爸爸了 上尉
Good luck with that baby, Lieutenant
所有人都知道了?
Does everybody know?
要员们都知道了
All the important people
谁家要员?
The important people to who?
你?
For you?
估计是
I guess so
我要去看看那帮小子了
I'm gonna go brood the boys
嗨 等下
Hey hold on one second
我带了这个想要你提前看一下
I brought it here cause I want you to read it before
我是个值得信任的长官
I'm trusted officer...
但是老实说
and but to be honest with you
我曾考虑打报告
I was thinking to calling the commander
让你回家
trying to get you home
但是事情愈演愈烈
And now worse picked up so much
觉得你非在不可了
I feel like we really need you here
你还记得我们在阿拉玛最后一次巡航吗?
You remember our last cruise on Alamar?
记得
Yeah
当最后要完成任务的时候 你说我可以走了
When you got that final turn over op you said I don't need to be there
我当时躺在床上 一心只想着回家
I was lying in bed, and I realized all the thing I need do now was go home
但是要是那时候有个万一
But if something went south in your op
我绝对会终身抱憾
I would always regret not being there with you
我很感激你一直以来的照顾 戴夫
I appreciate you're taking care of me big time, Dave
不过有时我也还是会厚皮脸的偷懒
But I'm working sometimes with the brass
要是可以
If I can
事情慢慢好转
And things slow down
我就给自己放个两周假
I'm gonna get 2 weeks off
要是可以我也会
I'll leave the works now eitherway,
真的
I really do
但要是不行
But if it doesn't
我就只能把这信折成纸飞机送出去了
I'm gonna take this piece of paper and I'll make it into nice paper airplane
尽力吧
Bid it
非洲海岸
AFRICAN COAST
很好
Good, we're good
601 浮出水面160尺
601, emerge the ship at 160 feet
出发 出发
- guide, guide
兄弟们 谢谢你们迅速赶到
Hey guys thank you for being here so fast
请坐
Grab a seat, please
谢谢
Thank you
你们会有斗牛犬分队的空中支援
You have Bulldog overhead
我们掩护你潜入
We need you te get in, grab the intel
把情报带回来
and down to back to us
有问题吗?
Do you have any questions?
长官 我有疑问
Sir, I have a question
我们已设定了汇合时间
We have the rally point time
要是他们没按计划出现
What if the meeting doesn't take place as schedule
我们需要盯梢多久?
How long do you want us to stay on target?
问得好
That's one counts
所以待会儿我会制定后备B计划
So, I plan on B out there for a while
遵命
Check
没问题了吧?
Are we good?
没问题了 长官 是的长官
Think so Sir. Yes Sir.
雷 阿加伊 我快到了
Ray - Ajay, I'll reached up
- 准备引你们出仓 - 开门 完毕
- and ready to check each other out - Grab the door, clear.
索马里
SOMALIA
找到目标了吗?
Do we have visual?
找到了
Yeah
三辆卡车靠近中
Got three trucks moving in
一辆加油车 两辆吉普车
a fuel truck, 2 jeeps,
最后一辆坐了一帮人
Some skinnies in the back
前后车距大约在50码左右
One at the last fifty count
听到没?
Do you hear that?
那是我们的目标
Yeah, think that our plan
是啊 来了
Yeah, we get some inbound
是时候现身了 上帝!
About time he's gonna showed up, Jesus!
把相机给我
Give me my camera
嘿 雷 有两架飞机在目标区
Hey Ray, we got two birds down here in the field
肯定是我们的目标
It's obvious our pass
没有尾翼编号
No tail ID's
记下没?
You got that?
记下了 没有尾翼编号
check,  no tail IDs
雷 我最后一次当监察员的时候
Ray, last time I checked
你还在非洲 是吧?
you were in Africa, right?
是啊
Yeah
为什么问这个?
Why, what's up?
老兄 大约有16个菲律宾人在那边
Dude, these like 16 Filipinos down there
都在朝麦加祷告呢
all praying to Mecca right now
菲律宾人?
Filipinos?
菲律宾人不会这么瘦骨嶙峋的
Filipinos definitely not skinnies
他们在给谁做祷告呢?
Who pick up the praying?
除非是抓了些俄国人
unless he's picking up some Russian
你们两个过来
You two come here
小心抬这些箱子 听到了没?
Be very careful with these boxes, do you hear me?
敢摔掉一个 就送你们上西天
Drop one of these and you are all going to heaven
你要转机
you will switch planes
选择不同地点入境
And enter through two different border crossings
小心点
be careful
一旦登岛 你的人有足够时间准备
Once on the island, your men will have time to finish preparations
我的朋友会一路陪行
A friend will be with you on the plane
帮你把余下的路途安排妥当
and help the rest of the way
斗牛犬分队 斗牛犬分队
Bulldog, Bulldog
无线电测试 完毕
we have around and we checked, over
收到 完毕
Get check, copy
收到 请注意
Roger get check, be advised,
我们发现两架空载飞机飞向东部
we got 2 sterile aircraft departing to the East
方位是
at following location
10,P,L,S
Ten Kappa Lima Sierra
检测到目标 请回复 完毕
Please advise, when you intel the target, over
收到 重复
Roger, copy
两架飞机 P,L,S
two aircraft ...Location Ten Kappa...
长官 你不会相信的
Hey Chief, you are not gonna believe this
雷和阿加伊监视的其中一架飞机
One of the planes Ray and Ajay tagged,
刚刚降落在墨西哥海岸的赛德罗斯岛上
just landed on Cedros Island of  the coast of Mexico
搭载了莎保和几个不知名的圣战主义者
It has Shabal with unknown number of jihadist
开玩笑吧这是?
Are you kidding me?
不 我们居然抢先了一步
No, it looks like we're getting ahead of target
还有 队长和他的突击艇队已经出发了
Well, Senior and his sweep motor punching out,
他们到时会上报更多详细情报
they should call a little more intel for shore sea
好的
All right
南太平洋
SOUTH PACIFIC
我不知道我们还要持续多久
I don't know how long we'll stay
再等些日子吧
Hold on Baby
保重
Be safe
我会的 我要挂了 亲爱的
You know I will, I gotta to go, Honey
我爱你
I love you
我也爱你
乔安 我不想和他们玩
Joann, I don't want to play with these
你在听吗? 没什么好担心的
Are you listening? There's nothing to worry about
好吗? 我们稍后再谈
OK?I'll talk to you soon.
布瑞沃 阿尔法 我们在二百米外
Bravo Alpha, we're 200 meters out
目标在右方 目标在右方
We got you have a Tango on your starboard side, Tango on your starboard side
维克 查理 侦察到敌方目标
Winky Charlie, we have visual on Tango
巴博 12点方向有敌情
Bubble, you have a Viper on 12 O'clock
出去!出去!
Get out! Get out!
安全!
Clear!
驾驶仓安全!
Bridge secure!
长官 船上安全
Senior, you're clear
中午好 最近过的如何?
Good afternoon, how are you?
不错 你会塞尔维亚语吗?
Right. Do you speak Serbian Croatia?
俄语呢?
Russian
你是俄国人?
You're Russian?
是的
Yes
我不说俄语
Do not speak Russian
说英语行不?
English ok?
挺好
English is fine
那就说英语吧
Let's do that
给他松绑吧 谢谢
Can you cut him loose, please
让你舒服点 你不会做出什么出格的事吧?
If you cut loose, you will not do anything crazy, right?
疯子伊凡(电影《追击红色十月号》)
Crazy iron, so to speak.
你是俄国人 对吧?
So you Russian, yeah?
是啊
Yes, I am.
你还好吧?
Are you all right?
我挺好 谢谢
Yes I'm good, thank you
不客气
You're welcome
我还不知道你的名字
I'm sorry, I don't know your name
我叫奥特
I'm Otto
- 奥特? - 很高兴见到你
- Otto? - Yes, nice to meet you
你呢?
And you are?
克里斯托
Christo
克里斯克?
Chrisko?
克里斯托
Christo
特拉伊科维奇?
Traskovich?
嘿 兄弟 我们要把这次行动做成了
Hey Brother, we need to make this hit count
因为我要推荐一个新指挥官
Beause I'm ready  promote new Liutenant commander  ...
我就可以去白宫工作了
I'm working at the White House
不是吧 你以为在玩传球呢
Oh man, looks carry football
看来还是让我当比较好
It was better let me carry that thing
开玩笑吧 兄弟
Oh no kidding, man
你知道吗 奥特 无论如何
Hey you know Otto, eitherway,
你还是得娶妻生子的 兄弟
there has to be some quality time for your the new family, Bro
是啊 所以这次就利落的干一场吧
Yeah man, now is gonna be a good clear move,
但是 要是我干掉了那些垃圾
but, I'll be a powerful in-commander
估计我也是个华丽的指挥官
if I suppose to shoot bad guys and few nurglars
是啊 但事实是
Yeah, well, truth to be told
你除了是个优秀通信员一无是处了
you will never good be an operator anyway
行了 兄弟
Come on man,
- 你知道你很挫 - 是啊
- you know you suck - yeah
嗨 别生气 别生气
Hey, come on, come on
你的游船很华丽
You sitting on wonderful boat,
棒极了
Fabulous
我叫它"星际飞船"
I believe it's called "starship"
"星际飞船"?
"starship"?
我喜欢听你说"星际飞船"的口音
I love the way you say "starship"
很像俄国人
It's like Russian
就像那个在星际迷航里的家伙 叫什么来着?
Like guy in Star Trek, what's his name?
史科特 不好意思 斯科特
Scotty, I'm sorry, Scott
我不知道
I would not
你没看过星际迷航?
You never seen Star Trek?
没看过
No
怎么可能
That's insane
我有个问题 老兄
So, here's the problem, pal
你是一直很有钱
You're with a lot of money
还是你曾经很有钱?
Or you were with a lot of money?
我想我一直很有钱
I believe I still have
- 真的? - 真的
- You do? - Yes
好吧
All right
老实告诉你真相吧
Let me tell you how the world works there
克里斯克
Chrisco ...
是克里斯托
It's Christo
什么?
sorry?
- 克里斯托-  哦 懂了
- Christo - oh, of course
我不介意
Oh it's ok
老实告诉你真实的世界到底是怎样的吧
Let me tell you how the world really works
- 请说 - 这个船不再是你的了
- please - this is no longer your boat
从我步入那个门开始
Since I walk through that door,
你就不是当初那个有钱人了 不是了
you're not the same guy you used to be. You just not.
这些我无能为力
There's nothing I can do to stop that
我也帮不了你
Nothing I can do to help you right now
除非你愿意
unless you let me help you
我们可以一起合作 兄弟 我和你
We need to do this together pal, you and me
你和这群圣战主义者合作感觉如何?
So, how is you think you working with these jihadi folks then?
你是犹太人 对不?
Your're Jewish, right?
莎保是...什么?
Shabal is ...what?
你有发小吗?
Have you ever had a friend that you grew up with?
- 什么? - 你有发小吗?
- Sorry? - Have you ever had a friend that you grew up with?
有 - 有共同的兴趣爱好
Yes - like play interest,
像足球之类的
like soccer..
或者你们都玩些什么
Or what would you play,
- 棒球吗? - 差不多
- base ball probably, right? - probably
然后大家各奔东西 几年后又重新相遇
And anyone has his separate ways, and some years later you meet up
但是你完全没有认出他
And you totally didn't recognize the person
这就是我和莎保
That's what I have been with Shabal
我们有共同的爱好
We share a common interest
所以他有些与众不同的念头
So, he came up with his incredible idea
来自于他的信仰
because of his beliefs
我不需要被他同化
I don't necessarily share his beliefs
但他是个聪明人
But he's a smart guy
你知道吗?
You know?
就像
Almost like ...
你知道的 就像
you know, almost like...
像 这就是我
like, this is me.
而那是莎保
and that's Shabal
是吗?
Is it?
美国人就是中间者
And America is in between
中间者?
Is it?
就是这样
Yeah
很酷的理论 不是吗?
Cool concept, no?
- 这个? - 是的
- Right here? - Yes
你把这个当做一场游戏吗?
You think this is some kind of game?
是吗?你觉得这么做挺好玩?
Do you? You find this amusing?
- 我不觉得 - 你知道你都做了什么吗?
- I'm not find ... - Do you realize what you're doing here?
黑胡分队呼叫基地
Blackbeard actual to Blackbeard Main
目标布瑞沃
Host nation counterpart secured target Bravo
报告清除完毕 允许想目标阿尔法移动
Report strike all.You're clear to move on target Alpha
收到 像目标行进中
Roger Main, clear to target
我只和家人坦白
The only people I answer to is my family
和我的妻子和孩子
to my wife and to my child
其他一律免谈
and nobody else
赶时间办事吗?
Running late somewhere?
06:04
6 after 4
真的?
Really?
是的
Yeah
然后 问题是 兄弟
So ... Here's the problem pal
你爱你的家人 是吧?
You do love your family don't you?
是的
Yes I do
那你女儿呢?
And what about your daughter?
我女儿怎么了?
what about my daughter?
你想见她吗?
Are you looking forward to seeing her again?
每时每刻都在想她
Every minute on my life
我给你看这些 是想让你考虑清楚
I wanted you to see that,  so you can think about something
一些事情
very seriously
因为你的余生可能会在某个牢房里度过
Because you're gonna be sitting in a box somewhere
得到妥善和人道的待遇
You'll be treated properly and humanely
这孩子会长大成人 成家立业
That girl is gonna grow up, and she's gonna get married
而你的妻子则会另觅良人
and your wife is gonna find someone else
你会失去一切
And you're gonna miss everything
要是我做了一些
If I had done something
危及家庭的事情
that would endanger my family
我会像你一样感同深受
I would feel just like you do right now
你能保证不动我家人吗?
Do you promise not to touch my family?
我永远不会动你的家人
I would never touch your family
永远不会
I would not
你听过
Are you familiar with ...
瓷质球体炸弹吗?
"ceramic bullbearings"?
没有听过
No
那就想象一下 16件装满
Just imagine 16 suicide vests
瓷质球体炸弹的自爆背心
filled with ceramic bullbearings
可以逃脱任何金属探测器的检测
Slipping by every metal detector
通过美国所有检查站的检查
and every check-point in your country.
你觉得你们国家的经济会因此萧条吗?
Do you think your economy's fcuked now?
先想想媒体会作何反应
Just think what the Media is gonna do with this
911和这个比起来就黯然失色了
It's gonna make 9/11 look like a fcuking walking park, the Grand Central Park
所以 你说
So, you're telling me ..
有16个圣战主义分子身穿自杀背心
there is 16 jahadis wearing suicide vests
他们会步入国境
they're gonna walk right accross the border
那他们打算去哪儿?
So, where are they going ?
圣地亚哥 旧金山 休斯顿
San Diego, San Francisco, Houston
你挑哪儿 他们就到哪儿
You pick a city, they'll be there
进行到什么阶段了?
And this is happening now ?
我们谈话的时候就已经在进行中了
It's happening as we speak
你说什么?
say what?
我们谈话的时候就已经在进行中了
It's happening as we speak
怎么才能阻止他们?
How can you stop this?
我束手无策
I can't
塞德罗斯岛 墨西哥
CEDROS ISLAND, MEXICO
黑胡分队 呼叫李
Blackbeard -  Lee
全员就绪
Contain element set
收到
Roger
救命!
Help!
救救我!
Help me!
开火 开火 开火
Done, done, done!
黑箱分队 这里是黑胡分队
Blackpack This is Blackbeard,
我们在市中心的南郊教堂汇合
we're in contact midtown south of the church
李呼叫黑胡 需要火力压制
Blackbeard - Lee watch your post.
收到 准备开火
Over watch, prepare to engage
开火
Going hot.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
小心手榴弹！
Frag out!
威米 发现越境者向南逃跑了 他们上了卡车
Weimy, I got chase borders heading south, they pick up truck
看到了
I see them
艾可 两个人在卡车上
Echo, two guys in the truck
迫击炮!
Mortar!
小心手榴弹！
Frag out!
长官 长官!
Sir, sir!
LT 你还好吗?
LT, you all right?
见鬼
Damn
你检查一下那个箱子
You check that box huh?
好的
Yeah
就是个哑弹 怎么可能受伤?
Good thing that was a dart, how am I gonna hurt?
哇
woow
上帝
Jesus
这不是伊拉克人做的自杀式背心
These are not some bushky vest from Iraqi hut
这可是高速弹丸
These some high speed shit
我们应该找个地方处理一下这些东西?
Maybe we should put this somewhere else, huh?
桑尼 找个地方放这货吧
Hey Sonny, find somewhere to put this would you?
目标安全
Target secure
设置警戒区
set security
三个去南边 剩下的去北边
rest to the north, three south
这就是你们的目标
Here are your objectives
很好
Well ...
我为你们骄傲
I'm proud of you
我们现在是一家人了
We are family now
长官 目标已自爆 一切安全
Chief, target blasting up, everything secure
艾克彻  任务还未完成
Actual, mission not complete
随时待命 任务只完成了一半
Stand by for follow one You only got half that you had at cell
目标已完全 长官
Target secure, Sir
战斗还未结束
This fight isn't over yet
现在听好
Now listen,
另一半目标会利用墨西卡利
the other half that cell's gonna be crossing
地下通道在上午七点过境
the border using a tunnel network from Mexicali at 0700
我们会和当地政府协商
we're coordinating with State
现在直升机会把你们送出城外
but for now the birds will drop you all outside the city
那边联络员佩德罗斯指挥官会等你们
where your POC is Commander Pedros
我稍后给你详细的路线信息
I'll give you more details on route
艾克彻 收到没?
Actual, are you copy ?
收到 长官
Roger Maam.
好了 我们接到新任务了
Ok, we got the hill laming on the deck,
我们要去墨西哥南部和指挥官他们的小组汇合
we're gonna meet a Mexican South Commander and his team
他们会协助我们潜入目标地
They're gonna help infiLTrate the target,
然后一同参与突击
and join us on the assault
你在开什么玩笑?
What the hell are you talking about?
我们还没将他们一网打尽 长官
We didn't got all of them yet, Chief
剩余的人在哪里?
Where's the rest of it?
他们在墨西卡利的边境
They're in Mexicali,  on the border
好吧 那其他人呢 他们怎么回船上?
All right, and the rest of the boys, how they getting back to the ship?
好人查理号会继续待命 他们会派陆战队过来
Bon Homme Richard stayed on station, they're gonna send them Marine helmet
进行扫尾工作
head all back split to target,
完事后我们的人会和他们一起撤离
and when they're done, the boys will pull off with them
好的 我在想
Ok i'm thinking
让第一小队跟我走
squad 1 and myself roll out
好的 第二小队呆在这里
Perfect, squad 2 stay here, buttons up,
- 和陆战队一起撤离 - 好的
pulls out of the marines - Ok
但现在 在日出之前
But now we would go to put them to town
我们得把他们安置在镇上
and crushing the sunrise
另一组会在几天内到达德克萨斯
Gather group we're gonna take as following day, the wadis
我明白
comprendors
长官 谁命令我们去墨西卡利的执行任务?
Hey sir, who the hell clear us had to go to Mexicali anyway?
我们所有行动上头都一清二楚
this would do all that we up to the platform.
州政府部门决定的
States Department on it.
美国和墨西哥边境
Border Wall with Mexico
长官
Hey Sir
开启第二频道
channel 2
如果我们这样下去 会累死街头的
By this time on keep work like this, Jacky's gonna be squeezed and kicked out on road
如论如何 要是我们把任务快速搞定
however, if we had this target quick enough,
你就能穿越地道早点回家了
he jump on the burrow right at shit home
嘿 我可不用走地道回家
Hey, I gonna need no burrow
你请到两周的假期了吗
you got it two weeks
在飞机上打电话的时候
on the time I was there on the plane hall
对我回家的问题你可是犹豫不决啊
you were not convinced so let me go home,
但我现在很肯定的告诉你来负责这次行动吧
but I'm convinced gonna leave your ass in charge
墨西卡利 美国/墨西哥边境
MEXICALI,
US/MEXICO BORDER
长官
Sir
中尉
Lieutenant
看起来政府正在忙着和墨方面协调呢 是吧?
Seems our government have been very busy to make this possible, huh?
据说很困难
All the way the tough, from I heard
有些事情你必须明白
There is something that you have to understand
我的上司 他们害怕事态演变成
my superiors, they're very fearful of
墨版的摩加迪沙事件
Mexican "mogadishu"
他们重点强调了 不要重演黑鹰坠落的悲剧
no black hawk down, that's what they're saying, so
我们行动要尽量低调
we do need to stay under the radar
我完全明白 长官
I understand completely Sir.
你的小队能过来支援我感激万分
Your team presence here is greatly appreciated
但是时间紧迫 我们得开始行动了
But we're out of time, we need to move
告诉我 我们该去哪儿
Tell me where  we go
帮你把信息整理一下
Help piece these together for me.
情报表示他们在利用地道网
Our intel says they using a tunnel network,
但在一家牛奶厂房的下面
but it's under a milk factory
这些信息对你有帮助吗?
This mean anything to you?
我知道确切位置
I know exactly where it is
离这里不远
It's not far from here
那就是我们要去的地方
And that's where we going
墨西卡利大概没有比这环境更恶劣的地方了
From all of the places of Mexicali you could have been, this probably the worst
贩毒团伙几乎全方位部署了那个地区
The cartels control any of that from all the angles
他们的火力远远胜过我们
They had us heavily outgunned.
单是接近目标就很是困难
Simply reaching your target's gonna be very difficult
长官 我们的国家正面临威胁
Sir we have a thorn national's heading to our country
毋庸置疑 他们可不待见我们
needless to say, they're no big fan of ours
要是他们就在那个工厂里
If they are in that factory,
那就是我们的目的地
that's where we going
中尉 我会带你们到你们需要去的任何地方
Lieutenant, I'll take you anywhere you need to go
但你和你的战友们得做好打场恶仗的心理准备
But prepare your men for a bigger fight than you had imagine
你不但要和目标作战
You're not fighting at men
还要和那些保护目标的毒枭们火拼
you're also fighting the cartels that protecting them.
要是你们的目标成功进入了地下通道
If your targets make it into those tunnels
那就无以遁形了
they'll disappear like ghosts
你从这里进入隧道
You enter the tunnels right here
走几米后会到达岔口
You walk several miles to this fork
我的人会告诉你走那条路
my men will tell you which way to take
一旦你们到达指定地点
Once you get to this point
我的工作就结束了
My job is done
你们就只能靠自己了
You're on your own
中尉 我们现在就出发吧
Lieutenant, we're going now
收到
Roger that
长官 不要停下 我们身负重任
Chief, We'll not stopping, we'll rolling up on target hard
收到 预计30秒后到达
Roger that, should've there about 30 seconds up
屋顶有人!
SA, on the roof!
我们得快撤
We gotta go
快!
Now!
快 你留在这里
Come on. You stay here
长官 留两个人在这里看守
Sir, leave two men here
你们俩 留在这!
You two, stay here!
威米!
Weimy!
我需要你控制住这该死的家伙的火力
I need you to lock this shit down
小心!
Watch out!
你们去控制大门
You guys got the gate
走!
Go!
去前面!
Go to the front door!
快走!
Go!
等一下
One moment
在这里炸弹引爆
This is where you have to blow the bomb
怎么了?
What happens?
你会在天堂和你丈夫重逢的
You will meet your husband in heaven
引爆!
Boooooomb!!!!!!!!!
妈的 长官
Damn it, sir
真想和家人说说刚刚发生什么了
I could explain that one to my family
别说  这样就不用解释了
Keep back there, so I won't  have to, huh?
安全
Clear
手榴弹！
Grenaaaaaade!
长官 我来照顾他
Chief, I got him
继续前进 我掩护你
Keep going, I cover you
长官！
Chief!
突击二队 这里是突击一队
Assault 2, this is  Assault 1.
请注意 隧道安全 危机警报解除
Be advised, tunnel is secure, and all threats are neutralized
LT和长官战亡
LT and Chief are down.
重复 LT和长官战亡
I say it again, LT and Chief are down.
你父亲是个出色的人
Your father was a good man
没有他的童年是一个遗憾
Growing up without him is gonna be hard,
会很受伤
It's gonna hurt.
你会感到孤独
You feel alone,
会感觉迷失了方向
out to see with no shore and sight
但是你要记住 你流着你父亲的一样的血
Remember, you have your father's blood in your veins
原则造就了你的父亲的人格魅力
The code that make your father who he was
它也会让你成为真正的男子汉
is the same code that'll make you a man
你父亲的意志和价值观将由你继承
Your father's will, his values live on in you
正如你父亲钟爱的盒子彩绘的人物
Like those people who is in strange painting your father admired
我们的一生会经历很多
We man made of the boxes
法则
chambers of laws
胜利
and triumph
伤痛
and hurt
希望
and hope
还有爱
and love
没人可以比一个
No one's stronger than a man
驾驭感情和整理过去的人更加强大
who can harness his emotions and his past
把那些伤痛当做你人生前进的动力
use it as motivation to write
去书写新篇章吧
the most important letter of your life
你父亲临死前
Before he died,
让我交给你特库姆塞的这首诗
your father asked me to give you this poem by Tecumseh, a man he greatly admired
我说过我会把它折成纸飞机送出去
I told him I'd fold it into paper airplane
我想我正在这么做
and I guess that's what I'm doing
他想借这首诗对你说
Say on it on him, to you
好好生活让不要畏惧死亡
Live your life that the fear of death can never enter your heart
不可干涉别人的信仰
Trouble no one about his religion
尊重他人和他们的见解
respects others and their views
也希望他们同样尊重你
and demand that they respect yours
要热爱生命
Love your life..
诠释生命
Perfect your life..
以美好看待生命中的一切
beautify all things in your life..
把有限的生命
Seek to make your life long
奉献到无限的为人民服务中去
and of service to your people
当你濒临死亡
When your time comes to die
不要像那些心怀恐惧的人
Be not like those whose hearts are filled with fear of death
当他们大限将至 他们哭泣
So that one their time come, they weep,
祈求上天再多给他们点时间
and pray for little more time
去重复他们平庸的人生
to live their lifes over again and indifferently
你应唱起你死亡之歌 像个英雄回家般的
Sing your death song, and die like a hero
离去
going home...